Ricardo Piglia Papers, 1954-2016: Finding Aid C1513
Manuscripts Division
- Series 7: About Piglia, 1969-2011; 6 boxes
  - Subseries 2: Interviews, 1977-2007; 2 boxes
    - "El laboratorio del escritor" por María Inés Bonorino, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 6)
    - El Porteño Interview, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 7)
    - "Entrevista a Ricardo Piglia" by Teresa Orecchia, 2001; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 8)
    - "Habla Ricardo Piglia", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 9)
    - Interview with Ricardo Piglia, undated; 1 box (Box L-000023)
      Digitized/Reading Room Access Only: Digital access copies are accessible on a computer in RBSC's reading room. For preservation reasons, physical access to original tapes is restricted.
      Existence and Location of Copies
      32101047383813_1_a.mp3
      1 audiocassette; recording of an interview with Ricardo Piglia, undated. Side B was blank.
    - Printed Materials, 1992-2005; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 10)
    - Printed Materials - Magazines and Journals, 1980-2007; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 11)
    - Printed Materials - Magazines and Newsprint, 1982-1990; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 12)
    - "Reivindicación de la utopía: Reportaje a Ricardo Piglia y Josefina Ludmer" by Julio Ramos, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 13)
    - "Ricardo Piglia: entre Arlt y Borges", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 14)
    - Transcripciones generales, 1977-1986; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 15)
    - Transcripciones de las reuniones del Colectivo 12, 1997; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 16)
    - Typewritten and Print Cutouts of Interviews, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 17)
    - Untitled Interview About Nombre falso, 1995; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 18)
    - Various Interviews, 1995-1996; 1 folder (Box B-001168, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 3: Newspaper Clippings, 1969-2008; 2 boxes
    This section contains printed media materials related to Ricardo Piglia's work. Articles contain book reviews and other media coverage.
    - Dinheiro queimado - Spiralbound Notebook Collection, 1998-1999; 1 folder (Box B-001169, Folder 1)
    - Formas breves - Spiralbound Notebook Collection, 2003-2004; 1 folder (Box B-001169, Folder 2)
    - Respiración artificial - Collected Clippings, 1980-1988; 1 folder (Box B-001169, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Printed Matter, 1969-2008; 1 box (Box P-000099)
    - Photocopies of Newspapers, 1988-2005; 1 folder (Box B-001169, Folder 4)
    - Newspapers (Folder 1 of 2), 1982-1999; 1 folder (Box B-001169, Folder 5)
    - Newspapers (Folder 2 of 2), 1982-1999; 1 folder (Box B-001169, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 4: Events, 1985-2011; 1 box
    Contains printed materials relating to various literary and performing art events either about Piglia or were inspired by Piglia and his work.
    - "Cultura y política en la Argentina" - Universidad Nacional de Mar del Plata Facultad de Humanidades, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 1)
    - Entre ficción y reflexión - Centro de Estudios Lingüísticos y Literarios, México, D.F., 2005-2007; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 2)
    - Hommage à Ricardo Piglia - l'Université Paris-Sorbonne (Paris IV), 2008; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 3)
    - "Inauguración de la Feria del Libro", 2008; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 4)
    - "La literatura, tres historias de infancia" - Semana del autor, La Casa de América (Madrid), 2008; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 5)
    - Plata quemada: Rhapsodie pour violon solo et grand orchestre à cordes, 2006; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 6)
    - Various Events, 1985-2011; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 7)
- Series 8: Others Work on Piglia, 1963-2005; 2 boxes
  Alphabetically, by folder title with the exception of the last folder that was added after initial processing.
  This series contains typewritten and computer print outs drafts and printed materials on other writers work on Ricardo Piglia..
  - "A libertade do pastiche" by Walter Melo Miranda, circa 1989; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 8)
  - Artificial Respiration Translated by Daniel Balderston, 1981; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 9)
  - Argentina-s: Ricardo Piglia dialoga con la generación del 37 en la discontinuidad, dissertation by Laura Beatriz Demaría, 1996; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 10)
  - "Between Arlt and Borges: An Interview with Ricardo Piglia" by Marina Kaplan, circa 1987-1989; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 11)
  - "¿Es propiedad? Indeterminación genérica, intertexualidad, diseminación en un texto "de" Ricardo Piglia" by John Deredita, 1979; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 12)
  - "Homenaje a Roberto Arlt" o la literatura como plagio" by Jorge Fornet, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001170, Folder 13)
  - Incomplete Manuscript on the Boom and Piglia, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 1)
  - "La modificación" and "Piglia: las pruebas de la historia" by José Sazbón, 1979-1983; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 2)
  - "La relación dialógica entre ficción e historia en "Respiración artificial" de Ricardo Piglia" by Edgardo Horacio Berg, circa 1989; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 3)
  - " Respiração artificial: um manual de pesquisa histórica" by Eliane Marta Teixeira Lopes, 1994; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 4)
  - "Processos de ficcionalización en Respiración artificial" by Rita De Grandis, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 5)
  - Works About Respiración artificial, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 6)
  - Various Others Work on Piglia, 1998; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 7)
  - Various Others Work on Piglia, 1981-2005; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 8)
  - "Algunas notas sobre "Literatura y Marxismo"" by Paolo Chiatini, 1963; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 9)
- Series 9: Others Work, 1970-1996; 2 boxes
  This series contains materials Piglia collected about others work.
  - Collected Printed Materials, circa 1980; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 10)
  - "Martí: La guerra desde las nubes" and Other Printed Materials by Arcadio Díaz Quiñones, 1995-1996; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 11)
  - Short Essays Possibly By Students, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001171, Folder 12)
    Includes print out drafts of short essays by Luis Guzmán, Guillermo Martínez, Oliverio Coelho, Martin Kohan, Juan Diego Incardona, Claudia Piñeiro, Federico Jeanmaire, Federico Romani, Ariel Bermani, Pablo de Santis, and Juan Forn.
  - Various Others Work, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001173, Folder 3)
  - Various Others Work, circa 1970-1987; 1 folder (Box B-001173, Folder 4)
- Born-Digital Materials, 1990-2015; 1 box
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  AM.2017.144
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Access to digital material in this collection is available on-site in the Special Collections Firestone Reading Room. Requests to access digital material from this collection must be placed at least 3 days in advance. For more information please contact Special Collections Public Services staff.
  Materials have been maintained in their original order, as received by the repository.
  Consists of born-digital materials, including files extracted from three floppy disks (3.5"), as well as optical media, including DVDs and CDs. The floppy disks consist of about 28 digital folders and 70 digital files, dating from January 1999 to July 2003. The optical media items consist of about 13372 digital folders and 85314 digital files, dating from 1990 to 2015, and primarily consist of DVDs containing Piglia's computer backups. The majority of the files consist of Word and PDF documents containing various drafts by Piglia; notes; corrections; correspondence; academic and teaching files, including numerous files from Piglia's tenure at Princeton University; documents related to conferences, presentations, trips; and others. Also included are various JPEG files, including images of Piglia participating in the second Encuentro Nacional de Bibliotecas Populares, and black-and-white images included in a DVD labeled, "Fotos MdP. Archivo Barili + Familia Piglia."
  Titles are taken from handwritten labels. Disk and optical media numbers refer to the order in which the imaging was attempted. Disk001 and optical008 were unsuccessfully imaged, but may be added in the future if a solution is found. Optical010 is a duplicate and was not imaged.
  - Originales de archivo I, 2003 July 06-2003 July 07; AM.2017.144_disk002; 21 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
    Se incluyen los siguientes expedientes: "Argentinishten Stagen"; "En familia"; "En la casa de Esteban"; "La paraguaya"; "Originales en conjunto"; "Rusos blancos"; "Soglidatay"; "Trata de blancas"; y "Un general."
  - El laboratorio del escritor, 1999 January 14-2001 April 25; AM.2017.144_disk003; 41 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - Sarmiento escritor (Word 97), 2000 December 12-2000 December 23; AM.2017.144_disk004; 8 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - Backup MacBook Pro - rpiglia - 19 oct 13, circa 1990s-2015; AM.2017.144_optical001; 10712 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - Backup iMac G4 - Ricardo Piglia - 25-08-05, 1990 September 02-2005 August 25; AM.2017.144_optical002; 9160 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - R. Piglia backup - 16 feb 10, circa 1990s-2010; AM.2017.144_optical003; 16680 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - Piglia backup all - osg - 2/7/07, circa 1990s-2007; AM.2017.144_optical004; 27435 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - Piglia - 2-2-2012, circa 1990s-2012; AM.2017.144_optical005; 20175 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - Fotos MdP. Archivo Barili + Familia Piglia, circa 2000-2015; AM.2017.144_optical006; 1108 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - Fotos incorporadas el 21/04/2009, fotos del archivo de Melina Piglia, circa 2009; AM.2017.144_optical007; 19 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - 2º Encuentro Nacional Bibliotecas Populares, circa 2009 May; AM.2017.144_optical009; 18 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)
  - Proyecto Venus 01: Tecnologías de la amistad, circa 2003; AM.2017.144_optical011; 7 digital files; 1 box (Box L-000023)